Bob Considine Papers
Bob Considine Papers
- Subject files
  - Little League Foundation Trustees Meeting, June 9, 1961 (Box 16)
  - The Log Cabin (newspaper), Sep. 18, 1840 (Oversize 1)
  - Lottery data, 1956; 2 folders; clippings and correspondence (Box 16)
  - Lottery data, 1951; 1955-1956; printed material (Box 16)
  - Louise Baer Memorial: A Girl to Remember, 1951; souvenir book of remembrances; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1947; press releases, speeches, interviews (Box 16)
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1949; press releases, speeches, interviews (Box 17)
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1962-1964; correspondence regarding article; includes 2 photographs (Box 17)
  - MacArthur Memorial Foundation, Douglas MacArthur Statesman Scholarship, undated (Box 17)
  - Mahoney, David J., 1972 (Oversize 2)
  - Maps (Box 17)
  - Meeting announcements and invitations, 1943; 1949-1950,; 1957-1958,; 1962,; 1968,; 1970-1971,; undated (Box 17)
  - Melton, James, Jul 1947; letter about him, from John Daniels (Box 17)
  - Membership cards (Box 17)
  - Men of Destiny (television series), circa 1960; promotional brochure regarding series of television shorts starring Considine narrating the lives of famous men, from series producer Pathé News (Box 17)
  - Meyner, Robert B. (governor of New Jersey), 1954-1958; 2 folders; biographical data (Box 17)
  - Meyner, Robert B. (governor of New Jersey), 1957-1958; clippings about (Box 17)
  - Meyner, Robert B. (governor of New Jersey), 1957-1958; clippings about (Box 18)
  - Music scores (Box 18)
  - Mutual of Omaha sponsorship, 1964; undated (Box 18)
  - National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences, 1973; souvenir Emmy ballot pencil (Box 18)
  - Negatives (Box 18)
  - "A Newspaperman's Prayer," by Considine (Box 18)
  - Newspaper data, 1957; clippings and quotes (Box 18)
  - Newspaper data, 1953-1957; published material (Box 18)
  - Nixon, Richard, Feb. 7, 1969; booklet containing remarks made to employees of the Dept. of Commerce (Box 18)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1962; correspondence regarding article pub Nov. 8, 1962 "Open Letter to a Defeated Politician" (Box 18)
  - Non-Violent Action Against Nuclear Weapons, 1958 (Box 18)
  - Notepads, undated; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Oakland Naval Hospital, 1968-1969; clippings and photographs (Box 18)
  - Office memos, 1952-1965; undated; 3 folders (Box 19)
  - "Old Age No. 1", 1955-1956; clippings and research material (Box 19)
  - "Old Age No. 2", 1954-1956; clippings and research material (Box 19)
  - Olympics, 1956; clippings (Box 19)
  - "On the Line" program pitch (Box 19)
  - "On the Line" transcripts (NBC Radio), 1957 (Box 19)
  - "The One and Only Solution to the Farm Problem" by Despain, Donald, Vantage Press, 1961 (Box 19)
  - Oppenheimer case, 1954 (Box 20)
  - "Over 80" series, correspondence, clippings, photographs, notes on people 80 years of age or older; includes information on Irving Berlin (including a score), James A. Farley, Harry Hershfield (including a hand-drawn cartoon), Robert Moses, Eddie Rickenbacker, and Adolph Zukor (Box 20)
  - "Over 80" series, miscellaneous (Box 20)
  - Overseas Press Club of America, 1947-1965 (Box 20)
  - Paley, William S., 1965; memos (Box 20)
  - Parachuting championships, 1962; program booklet of the Sixth World Sport Parachuting Championshios in Orange, MA, August 11-Sept. 3, 1962 (Box 20)
  - Passport (Box 20)
  - Pattillo, Frank A., Colonel, 1951-1954 (Box 20)
  - Photographs
    - Aer Lingus publicity photos with Considine's book, "It's the Irish", undated (Box 20)
    - Aviation (Box 20)
    - Bendix, William, 1948; undated (Box 20)
    - Blind children, photo poster (Oversize 3)
    - Camp Mascoma, 1955; photo album of son Dennis at summer camp (Box 20)
    - Conn, William David "Billy" [fighter], undated (Box 20)
    - Considine solo (Box 20)
    - Considine solo (Box 21)
    - Considine with wife Millie and others (Box 21)
    - Considine with others, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Craig, Elisabeth May Adams, 1951; signed (Box 21)
    - Davidson, Howard Calhoun, 1945; signed (Box 21)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., undated (Box 21)
    - Family (Box 21)
    - Fishing at Palm Beach, Florida, 24-26 Aug 1973; scrapbook, Soviet Union Ambassador Anatoly Dobrynin's visit on Armand Hammer's yacht, with Considine and others (Oversize 2)
    - Gabor, Zsa Zsa, undated (Box 21)
    - Hearst, William Randolph at Motion Picture Pageant, 1932; signed (Box 21)
    - Hearst, William Randolph Jr. with Considine and others, includes airplane trips, meetings, and in Hong Kong (Box 21)
    - Honors and awards, album with photos of award certificates, trophies, and plaques that Considine received (Oversize 4)
    - Hope, Bob, undated (Box 22)
    - Japan (Box 22)
    - Japanese air and naval photos of invasion of Pearl Harbor, released as "Official U.S. Air Force Photo" (Box 22)
    - Lieb, Frederick (American sportswriter), undated; signed (Box 22)
    - Meyner, Robert B. [governor of New Jersey], photographs of photographs, with handwritten captions (Box 22)
    - Military, includes some with Considine as war correspondent (Box 22)
    - Mutual of Omaha, shots of Considine with guests on his show "On the Line" (Box 22)
    - New Guinea, 433rd Weapons Squadron, U.S. Air Force WWII, mostly at Biak and nearby bases showing soldiers and day-to-day life (Box 22)
    - Nixon, Richard, with copy of "Ask Me Anything" by Considine et al., circa 1960 (Box 22)
    - Nuclear bomb explosion (Box 22)
    - Outdoors with others (Box 22)
    - Pieta, move of Michelangelo's famous statue from the Vatican to New York for the 1963/1964 World's Fair (Box 22)
    - Pope Pius XII, undated (Box 22)
    - Rice, Henry Grantland [American sportswriter], undated (Box 22)
    - Ruark, Robert, undated (Box 22)
    - Ruth, Babe, 1921; 1923,; 1947-1948,; undated (Box 22)
    - Scrapbook, Trans World Airlines Super-G Constellation International Preview Flight, April 1-11, 1955 (Box 23)
    - Scrapbook, Trip to Russia (Oversize 14)
    - Social events, 2 folders; includes dinners, speeches, large group photos (Box 23)
    - Space (Box 23)
    - U.S. Air Force (Oversize 3)
    - Vietnam (Oversize 3)
    - Miscellaneous of others (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous oversize (Oversize 3)
  - Poems and prayers, 1932; 1958,; undated (Box 23)
  - Political buttons (Box 23)
  - Politics, international, 1950-1962 (Box 24)
  - Politics, U.S., 1950-1964 (Box 24)
  - Pope Paul VI visit to Israel, 1964-1965; explanation of sites and map of the route taken, by Zev Vilnay; tentative passenger list on Papal plane, Rome to New York Oct 4 (Box 24)
  - Press badges, cards, and passes (Box 24)
  - Press Club of San Francisco, 1970; "Gang Dinner" souvenir caricature drawing (Oversize 4)
  - Promotional materials (Box 24)
  - Questions for Bob Considine, undated; for students of journalism, possibly Famous Artists Schools related (Box 24)
  - Radio scripts (Box 24)
  - Receipts, 1948-1958 (Box 24)
  - Recipes and menus, 1834; 1946,; 1957,; undated (Box 24)
  - "Reporter's Notebook" by Considine (Box 24)
  - Reports
    - Alaskan Counties, 1959; a study for the establishment of counties in the then-new state of Alaska (Box 24)
    - American Rocket Society, "Aspects of the Law of Space Activities" by Paul G. Dembling, 1960 (Box 24)
    - "Brief Progress Report on the Political Reorientation of Japan," General Headquarters, Supreme Commander for the Allied Forces, 1949 (Box 24)
    - Chicago Crime Commission, 1953 (Box 24)
    - Congressional Record, 1962 (Box 24)
    - DMS Market Intelligence Report: Military and Civil Aircraft, 1965 (Box 24)
    - DMS Market Intelligence Report: Rockets, Missiles, Spacecraft, 1965 (Box 25)
    - "Dodger Fans of the World, Unite!" by Arthur King, 1957 (Box 25)
    - Good Samaritan Society, London, 1956-1957 (Box 25)
    - Hearst Newspapers, Writing Contest winners and "Editor-to-Editor Information Report No.10", 1956; 1963 (Box 25)
    - "Japanese Economic Statistics", General Headquarters, Supreme Commander for the Allied Forces, 1960 (Box 25)
    - Mutual of Omaha, Financial Report, 1959 (Box 25)
    - NASA (various Project Mercury related), 1959-1960 (Box 25)
    - New Family Center of Japan [Tokyo], 1954 (Box 25)
    - New York Athletic Club, 1963 (Box 25)
    - New York City. Department of Welfare. Bureau of Alcoholic Therapy, 1947; 1951 (Box 25)
    - "A Showman's Guide to Better Business" Twentieth-Century Fox, 1950s (Box 25)
    - United Nations. "Violation of Human Rights in South Viet-Nam", 1963 (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944; 1950,; 1957 (Box 25)
  - Reprints, 1913; 1946-1965,; 1975,; undated (Box 25)
  - Reprints of Considine columns, 1953; 1965,; undated (Box 25)
  - Resumés, 1957-1964 (Box 25)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1957-1958 (Box 25)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1958 (Box 26)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1958; clippings (Box 26)
  - Revell, Nellie, 1937; 1950,; 1957-1958,; undated (Box 26)
  - Reviews
    - "Ask Me Anything", 1959-1960 (Box 26)
    - The Babe Ruth Story, 1948 (Box 26)
    - Eisenhower LP, 1969; review of phonograph disc narrated by Considine (Box 26)
    - "It's All News to Me" (book), 1967 (Box 26)
    - "It's the Irish" (book), 1961 (Box 26)
    - Man Against Fire, 1955 (Box 26)
    - "The Men Who Robbed Brinks" (book), 1961 (Box 26)
    - "The Remarkable Life of Dr. Armand Hammer", 1975 (Box 26)
    - "Ripley: The Modern Marco Polo", 1960-1961 (Box 26)
    - "Toots" (book), 1969 (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961; 1967,; 1969,; undated (Box 26)
  - Rocket Sled (Deceleration), Col. John P. Stapp, 1954-1956 (Box 26)
  - Route maps [of air flights] (Box 26)
  - Russia horse racing, 1958; 1962,; undated (Box 26)
  - Sacks, Emanuel, 1956-1958 (Box 26)
  - Schedules for radio and TV, 1946; 1957 (Box 27)
  - Schlieker, Willy, 1946-1947; 1956,; 1958 (Box 27)
  - Score cards undated (Box 27)
  - Scripts for unproduced movie, and radio show (Box 27)
  - Search message, undated; air and naval search around Umboi Island-Vitiaz Strait, presumably from WWII (Box 27)
  - Shor, Toots [Bernard], 1967-1969; undated (Box 27)
  - Sister Bernard, 1965; 1971 (Box 27)
  - Smith, Jack, 1946-1947; 1960,; 1966-1970,; undated (Box 27)
  - Space medicine, 1952; 1958-1959; articles by and about Dr. Hubertus Strughold (Box 27)
  - Stagg, Amos Alonzo, 1957; 1962 (Box 27)
  - Stassen, Harold E., 1946-1947 (Box 27)
  - Statements of commissions and royalties, 1949-1958 (Box 27)
  - Sterling Movies USA Inc., undated; promotion and press kit (Box 27)
  - Strughold, Hubertus, See Space medicine, above.
  - Summary from the Official Catholic Directory, 1962 (Box 27)
  - Survey, 1963; Albuquerque Annual Business Survey (Box 27)
  - Taxi drivers, New York City, 1967 (Box 27)
  - Telecasts (Box 27)
  - Tello, Manual, 24 Oct 1961; address on the 16th anniversary of the United Nations, at the Mexican Embassy in Washington D.C. (Box 27)
  - Telephone messages, 1962-1964; undated (Box 27)
  - "That Year", undated; TV show proposal (Box 27)
  - Thorton, Robert Lee, 1955-1957 (Box 27)
  - Tickets, air line, 1956-1964 (Box 27)
  - Tickets, Irish Hospitals' Sweepstake, 1957 (Box 27)
  - Tickets, miscellaneous, 1956; 1958,; undated (Box 27)
  - Tregaskis, Richard [American journalist and author], 1973; includes photograph taken 1 week before his death (Box 27)
  - Tribute to Louise Baer, by Irving Wright at her funeral, 1950 (Box 27)
  - Tributes to Considine, 1975-1976 (Box 28)
  - Truman, Harry, 1964; interview (Box 28)
  - U-2, 1964; includes photos of plane (Box 28)
  - "Uncommon Valor", undated; promotional booklet for television series about the U.S. Marine Corps from General Teleradio (Oversize 1)
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA), undated (Box 28)
  - United States Army, 1974-1975; mostly about recruitment issues (Box 28)
  - University of Missouri, "A Stronger Free Press for a Better World", 1958; booklet announcing upcoming series of events honoring the American communications field (Box 28)
  - Vietnamese orphans, 1970; 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Virginia City, Nevada, 1949; undated (Box 28)
  - "Visit of Richard Nixon President of the United States of America to the Middle East - Press Notes", June 1974 (Box 28)
  - West, Bill, 1975; St. John's Military Academy, Delafield, Wisconsin (Box 28)
  - Wilkes College commencement program, 1975 (Box 28)
  - William Randolph Hearst Foundation Third Annual Journalism Awards Rules and Regulations, 1962-1963 (Box 28)
  - Women's Titleholders Golf Association, 1946; 1951 (Box 28)
  - Wonder drugs, 1948-1950 (Box 28)
  - Young Island, St. Vincent, 1965 (Box 28)
  - Zeckendorf, William [American real estate developer], 1951-1954 (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 29)
- Manuscripts
  - Manuscripts by Considine
    - Address to the John Carroll Society, undated; spiritual and beneficent organization for Catholic professional laypersons in Washington, DC (Box 29)
    - Articles
      - Anyway -- We Tried (Box 29)
      - Autos, Safety and Your Life, article no. 3, 1966 (Box 29)
      - Baseball Wife [written for Cosmopolitan], Jun 1938 (Box 29)
      - Behold the TU-104 (Box 29)
      - Big Bill, about William Tatum Tilden II, American tennis player (Box 29)
      - Blunt Talk From Richard M. Nixon (Box 29)
      - Broadway Columnist [written for Cosmopolitan], Jul 1951 (Box 29)
      - Cancer no. 1-no. 4 (Box 29)
      - Castiglia, Jim (Box 29)
      - Churchill (Box 29)
      - Churchill, Winston, two articles about his funeral service (Box 29)
      - The Cirrhosis Club (Box 29)
      - Craig, about Craig Wood, American golfer (Box 29)
      - Dean, Jimmy (Box 29)
      - Democratic National Convention, Chicago, 1956 (Box 29)
      - The Doctor Who Made Faces, undated (Box 29)
      - The Downs and Ups of a People (Box 29)
      - Duke and Duchess of Windsor (Box 29)
      - Eichmann (Box 29)
      - European refugees (Box 29)
      - Ford, 8 articles about Henry Ford II (Box 29)
      - The Frantic Fifties, 1959 (Box 29)
      - Grantland Rice Memorial Lecture, 1958; named for Grantland Rice, noted American sportswriter (Box 29)
      - The Great Decider, 1957 (Box 29)
      - Hot Ice (Box 29)
      - How Russia Stole America's Atomic Secrets, 1952 (Box 29)
      - How to Write a How To Article (Box 29)
      - If I Were King (Box 29)
      - Indian Love Song, 1949 (Box 29)
      - Japan during the Korean War (Box 29)
      - Johnson, Lyndon, fragments (Box 29)
      - June Marie, 1928 (Box 29)
      - Kerensky, 2 copies (Box 29)
      - Korea during Korean War (Box 30)
      - Laughing Down to Rio (Box 30)
      - Let's Talk About Football (Box 30)
      - Life of My Grandmother (Box 30)
      - Luce (Box 30)
      - MacArthur, Douglas (Box 30)
      - Mission Unaccomplished (Box 30)
      - Mister Mustered Out... (Box 30)
      - My Life with Toots Shor (Box 30)
      - Napoleon's Balls (Box 30)
      - Newspaperman's Prayer (Box 30)
      - Niemöller, Martin (Box 30)
      - Nixon, Richard M. (Box 30)
      - The Nun and the Liberty Bell (Box 30)
      - Paley, William S., set of 7 articles about the CBS executive; typescript carbon, revised (Box 30)
      - Pride Goeth Before... (Box 30)
      - Project Mercury Space Program (Box 30)
      - Reading Time: 3 Shots (Box 30)
      - Target: Ike (Box 30)
      - Test [written for Cosmopolitan], Sep 1956 (Box 30)
      - They Fight With Their Feet (Box 30)
      - Think, regarding think tanks, particularly RAND Corporation (Box 30)
      - Todd, Thelma (Box 30)
      - The Unknown American Colossus (Box 30)
      - Velez, Lupe (Box 30)
      - Washington Hostess (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders; fragments or untitled (Box 30)
    - Books
      - Babe Ruth, undated (Box 30)
      - Bob Considine's Christmas Stocking, 1958 (Box 30)
      - Bugs Baer book [unpublished], background material for a book Considine never really began; original folder titles retained, there is no Folder 3
        - "Folder 1 Biographical stuff and stories by those who knew Bugs" (Box 30)
        - "Folder 1 Biographical stuff and stories by those who knew Bugs", oversize material originally in Folder 1 (Oversize 1)
        - "Folder 2 Short pieces by Bugs" (Box 31)
        - "Folder 4 Short Stories - George Rector" (Oversize 1)
        - "Folder 5 Sports Articles" (Oversize 1)
        - "Folder 6 Letters to and from Bugs" (Box 31)
        - "Folder 7 Bugs and the Banshees" (Box 31)
        - "Folder 8 Louise Baer" (Box 31)
      - Christian Brothers of Ireland [unpublished], 4 folders; includes "Notes for a biography of Brother Edmund Rice, Founder of the Christian Brothers of Ireland, collected 1958" (Box 31)
      - Eisenhower book [unpublished], undated; outline (Box 32)
      - Fire Insurance, Protection from Disaster, undated (Box 32)
      - Innocents at Home, 1949; annotated as "Copy for the Press" (Box 32)
      - It's All News to Me, 1967; undated
        - Draft, Chapters I-III (Box 32)
        - Draft, Chapters IV-VI (Box 32)
        - Draft, Chapters VII-VIII (Box 32)
        - Draft, Chapters IX-XI (Box 33)
        - Draft copies of chapters, Caveat Emptor, Cissy, Fun n Games, INS (RIP), Moonlighting (2 copies), Intrusion (Box 33)
        - Draft copies of chapters, It Broadens One, Task Force (2 copies), The Fraudulent Art of Spooking, You Meet Such Interesting People, Big Game, Bigger Game, Endit (Box 33)
        - Miscellaneous draft fragments (Box 33)
        - Miscellaneous fragments, includes correspondence and an article "Tales of the INS" by Charles Einstein, and other correspondence Considine used in the INS chapter (Box 33)
        - Galley proof (Box 33)
        - Galley proof (Box 34)
      - It's the Irish, typescript draft; 2 folders (Box 34)
      - Lengthened Shadows [unpublished], rough outline of a book idea (Box 34)
      - MacArthur, Douglas, unclear whether this is the 1942 book MacArthur the Magnificent or the 1964 book General Douglas MacArthur
        - Confidential research folder, evidently supplied by Julius Klein, newspaperman and Major General, to Considine; contains writings by Edward Ranzal, Tom Doherty, and Robert C. Richardson Jr. (Box 34)
        - Draft fragments (Box 34)
      - The Men Who Robbed Brinks
        - Background material, 1960 (Box 34)
        - Chapters 1-10 (Box 35)
        - Chapters 11-18 (Box 35)
        - Galley proof (Box 35)
      - Money is to Give Away [unpublished book about Irving Geist]
        - Draft [I], typescript (Box 35)
        - Draft [II], typescript (Box 35)
        - Draft [III], 10/27/72; typescript (Box 36)
        - Interview with Irving Geist, "#1", transcription (Box 36)
        - Interview with Irving Geist, "#2", transcription (Box 36)
        - Legal related, 1972; Irving Geist died while Considine was finishing the book; his family fought for it not to be published while Considine wanted to be paid (Box 36)
        - Miscellaneous, draft fragments, notes, research (Box 36)
      - Portrait of the NYAC [New York Athletic Club], 100th anniversary volume, typescript carbon drafts (Box 36)
      - The Remarkable Life of Dr. Armand Hammer
        - "Bloc Buster" "Final to N.Y. 10/30/74" Preface - chapter 12, draft typescript (Box 36)
        - "Bloc Buster" "Final to N.Y. 10/30/74" Chapter 13-Appendix E, 2 folders; draft typescript (Box 37)
        - Preface, 4 versions, not used in final book (Box 37)
        - "Bio" [chapter 1 Genesis of a Genius], 6 versions (Box 37)
        - "Rus" [chapter 2 Russia, Bolshevik Style], 3 copies (Box 37)
        - "Len" [chapter 3 Lenin The Ice Breaker], 2 copies (Box 37)
        - "Trot" [chapter 4 Trade and Trotsky], 2 copies (Box 37)
        - "Ford" [chapter 5 Fords in His Future], 3 copies (Box 37)
        - "frus" [chapter 6 Death of a Friend], 2 copies plus fragments (Box 37)
        - "Vic" [chapter 7 Invincible Victor Hammer] (Box 37)
        - "Pen" [chapter 8 The Pencil Mightier than the Sword], 2 copies (Box 37)
        - "Nur" [chapter 9 Early Raids on Nuremberg and Birmingham], incomplete (Box 37)
        - "Art" [chapter 10 El Dorado, Russian Style], 2 copies plus fragments (Box 37)
        - "Sales" [chapter 11 Moscow and Paris to Gimbels], 2 versions plus fragments (Box 37)
        - "Whiskey" [chapter 12 Friskey Whiskey], fragments (Box 37)
        - "Eric" [chapter 13 The Golden Bull], fragments (Box 37)
        - "Cam" [chapter 14 A New Sunrise at Campobello], 1 copy plus fragments (Box 37)
        - "Oxy" [chapter 15 Accidental Occidental], 2 copies (Box 37)
        - "Vig" [chapter 17 A Man of Many Faces], 3 copies (Box 37)
        - "K" [chapter 18 Back to the U.S.S.R.], 2 copies (Box 37)
        - "Exch" [chapter 19 Grandma Leads the Parade], 3 versions (Box 37)
        - [chapter 20 How to Deal With Ivan], various version fragments (Box 38)
        - "Press" [chapter 21 The Doctor and His Public], various versions and fragments, research material (Box 38)
        - "Law" [chapter 22 A Law unto Himself] (Box 38)
        - "Niz" [chapter 22 A Law unto Himself], 1 copy plus fragments (Box 38)
        - [chapter 26 The Aborted Coup] (Box 38)
        - "Epilogue", fragments (Box 38)
        - "Stock", several versions; unclear what chapter this relates to, as it includes direct passages from chapter 16 Allah's Messenger and others (Box 38)
        - "Trade", 2 copies; unclear what chapter this relates to, as "Chapter 19" is written on it, but the contents do not match chapter 19 of the book (Box 38)
        - Miscellaneous chapter fragments (Box 38)
        - Miscellaneous chapter notes, editorial comments (Box 38)
        - "Doing Business with the Russians", article by Armand Hammer incorporated into Considine's book (Box 38)
        - Galley proof, 2 folders; photocopy? (Box 38)
        - Interview with Armand Hammer, "AH1", Japan, Getty, Libya, others; transcribed, 2 copies (Box 38)
        - Interview with Armand Hammer, "AH 1-2-3", Whiskey, son, Occidental, others; transcribed, 2 copies (Box 38)
        - Interview with Armand Hammer, "AH4", "AH 4-8", Soviet Union businesses, bulls, oil, others; transcribed, 2 copies (Box 38)
        - Interview with Armand Hammer, "Hammer I-II", "Hammer III-IV", marriages, politics, Grandma Moses, others; transcribed (Box 39)
        - Interview with Neil H. Jacoby, transcribed (Box 39)
        - Interview with Victor Hammer, Armand's younger brother "Vic 1-2", transcribed, 2 copies (Box 39)
        - Photocopy of draft typescript of book, 2 folders (Box 39)
        - Research material, 2 folders (Box 39)
        - RX for Riches: the Remarkable Life of Dr. Armand Hammer, 2/10/75; galley photocopy of paperback edition (Box 39)
        - RX for Riches: the Remarkable Life of Dr. Armand Hammer, 3/25/75; 2 folders; galley photocopy of paperback edition (Box 40)
        - Suggested titles (Box 40)
      - St. Patrick's Cathedral [unpublished], 1958-1959; notes for a history of the building (Box 40)
      - They rose above it: True stories about men, women, and children who fought back in the face of pain, doubt, and dismay (Box 41)
        - Draft typescript, working title "Guts" (Box 41)
        - Draft typescript, working title "Guts #2", incomplete (Box 41)
        - Draft typescript, working title "Guts!", incomplete (Box 41)
        - Draft typescript, working title "They Call it Courage", incomplete (Box 41)
        - Draft typescript, working title "You Think You've Got Trouble?" (Box 41)
        - Miscellaneous drafts, incomplete chapters and unidentified pages (Box 41)
        - Miscellaneous background material, includes correspondence, columns by Considine (Box 41)
        - Miscellaneous background material, stories by Maria Isabel Caceres "Unforgettable Roberto Clemente"; John Reddy "Woody Guthrie: Father of the Folk Singers"; and Toots Shor "The Most Unforgettable Character I've Met" (Box 42)